write2000.com 2014-03-27

# Privacy Policy » Reading Plus

We at Taylor Associates Communications, Inc., (“Taylor Associates”) are committed to protecting the privacy of our customers, and we treat any information you share with discretion, care and respect. This notice describes Taylor Associates’ privacy policy for information we collect from individuals both online (on our website) and offline (through mail or telephone).

### What types of personal and non-personal information do we gather online and offline?

We gather personally identifiable information when you contact Taylor Associates by mail, phone, e-mail, visit our site or fill out requests for information through our advertisements and promotions. We collect only personal information that you provide to us such as: name, address, phone number, e-mail address, grade level of student enrolling in courses and shipping and billing information for orders (i.e., credit card number and expiration date). We may also record the types of product information you have requested as well as technical information about your workstation or local area network.

### How do we use the personal and non-personal information that we gather?

We use personally identifiable information for shipping and billing purposes, to respond to consumers’ requests, to provide consumers with special offers and to notify consumers of new product launches. Like most web sites, we may also add to the above personally identifiable information a variety of non-personal information such as: technical data including (but not limited to) your IP address (a unique number that identifies your access account on the Internet), domain and web browser information. We may track the page you visited before coming to our site, the page you link to when you leave, which of our pages you access and how long you spend on each page.

### How is non-personally identifiable data used?

We use non-personally identifiable data for internal business and marketing purposes, and share such data with third parties including current authorized Taylor Associates sales representatives.

### What about cookies?

We receive and store certain types of information automatically through the use of “cookies.” Cookies are files that your web browser places on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to track your experience with this web site, to tell us whether you have visited this site previously, to assist with login procedures for online courses and to help us determine if you came from a particular link or banner advertisement. You may set your browser to reject cookies, but this will limit some functionality of the site, particularly the login process to Reading Plus®. We do not use cookies to retrieve personal information about you from your computer.

### Do we disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties?

No personally identifiable information is shared with third parties unless you have provided personal information on behalf of your school, college, tutoring facility, optometric practice or similar organization and have requested a trial or more detailed product information. In these cases, we will provide your contact information to our authorized sales representatives so they may best assist you with sales related questions. If you do not want us to disclose this information to our authorized sales representatives, please write to us at: Taylor Associates Communications, Inc., 110 W. Canal St. Suite 301 Winooski, VT 05404 or call 1-800-732-3758 or e-mail us at info@readingplus.com with your full name in the subject line. Please be sure to include your first name, last name, address, city, state, zip code and phone number to ensure we can process your request. We will process your request promptly. Notwithstanding anything else in this policy, we may: (a) disclose personal and aggregate information when required by a valid legal mechanism such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order, or when we deem it necessary to protect the safety of site users, our employees or property; and (b) disclose personal information in the context of the sale of some or all of our assets.

### What about children’s privacy?

The site is not targeted to children, however, we do store information about children under the age of 13 that has been provided by parents or teachers for use in our online applications to improve the reading ability of children. We do not sell products for purchase by children; we sell children’s products for purchase by adults. Information collected from parents or legal guardians includes children’s name and grade. Parents have access to summary data collected for their child and can request a complete record of data including their child’s performance data within our online reading assessment and improvement courses. This data includes name, class assignment (when used through a school or institution) and all performance and assessment data collected. Summary information is accessible through the Parent/Student Report tab which is available within the student login area. Parents can review their child’s personal information, ask to have it deleted and refuse to allow any further collection or use of their child’s information. If at any time you decide that you would like your child’s information removed from our records, or would like to request all data collected on your child, please send an e-mail to info@readingplus.com with your name in the subject line and include your request within the body of the email.

### Except as authorized under COPPA, Taylor Associates will NOT:

Collect online contact information from a user under 13 without prior verifiable parental consent or teacher consent in the instances where Reading Plus® or Visagraph™ is used with students within a school or private organization. All information that is collected on users under the age of 13 is provided by parents or teachers.

Collect personally identifiable offline contact information from users under 13 without prior verifiable parental consent.

Distribute to third parties any personally identifiable information collected from children known to be under 13.

Entice a child under 13 by the prospect of a special game, prize or other activity to divulge more information than is needed to participate in our instructional activities.

### How are e-mail links treated?

We use e-mail links located on throughout our web site to allow you to contact us directly with any questions or comments you may have. We read every message sent in and try to reply promptly to each one. This information is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. We may also file your comments to improve the web site and learning programs or review and discard the information.

### Can I opt out of receiving communications from Taylor Associates Communications, Inc.?

Yes. We will process your request promptly. Please be aware that you may receive another contact before your name removal takes effect. We regret any inconvenience this may cause. If you do not wish to receive any communications, send an e-mail to info@readingplus.com with your full name in the subject line. Please include your first name, last name, address, city, state, zip code and phone number to ensure we can process your request.

### Links

This site may contain links to other web sites. Taylor Associates is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.

### How can I modify my personal information?

This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided: Send us a letter at the following address. Please include your first name, last name, address, city, state, zip code and phone number to ensure we can process your request. Taylor Associates Communications, Inc. 110 W. Canal St. Suite 301 Winooski, VT 05404.

### Will this policy change?

If at some future time there is a material change to our information usage practices that affect your personally identifiable information, we will notify you of the relevant changes on this site or by e-mail. If you are concerned about how your information is used, please check our web site periodically to review our current privacy policy.

### How do I contact the Web site?

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this Site, you may contact us: Privacy Officer, Inc. Taylor Associates Communications, Inc. 110 W. Canal St. Suite 301 Winooski, VT 05404

Updated: 1.10.14
